<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Justice perverted, and innocence &amp; loyalty oppressed, or, A detection of the corruptions of some persons in places of great trust in the government which would have been laid open the last  session of Parliament, according to the intentions of both Houses, had it not been prevented.</title>
            <author>Crosfeild, Robert.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1695</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 74 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 18 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A35158</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing C7245</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R7496</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">31355358</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 31355358</idno>
            <idno type="VID">110420</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A35158)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 110420)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1737:8)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Justice perverted, and innocence &amp; loyalty oppressed, or, A detection of the corruptions of some persons in places of great trust in the government which would have been laid open the last  session of Parliament, according to the intentions of both Houses, had it not been prevented.</title>
                  <author>Crosfeild, Robert.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>iv, 5-31 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Printed in the Year MDCXCV [1695]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Attributed to Robert Crosfeild by Wing (2nd ed.), and concerns corrupt practices within the navy.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: stained and tightly bound, with loss of text.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Great Britain --  History, Naval --  Stuarts, 1603-1714.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  William and Mary, 1689-1702.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-09</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02</date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02</date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:110420:1"/>
            <p>JUSTICE Perverted, AND INNOCENCE &amp; LOYALTY Oppreſſed. OR, <hi>A</hi> DETECTION OF THE CORRUPTIONS OF SOME Perſons in Places of Great Truſt in the Government; which would have been laid open the Laſt Seſſion of Parliament, according to the Inten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of both Houſes, had it not been prevented.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed in the Year MDCXCV.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="dedication">
            <pb facs="tcp:110420:2"/>
            <pb n="iii" facs="tcp:110420:2"/>
            <head>To the LORDS Spiritual and Temporal, and COMMONS in Parliament Aſſembled.</head>
            <p>IF we look back, and conſider how often, and to how high a degree His Majeſty hath expos'd His Royal Perſon this War; and what immenſe Sums of Money have been rais'd during the ſame, upon the Succeſs whereof not only the well-being of this Kingdom, but the Happineſs of <hi>Europe</hi> depends; one would then conceive the very Apprehenſion of theſe things was ſufficient to beget a generous Principle in all Perſons in Places of Truſt, and an Emulation in every Man to outvy each other in Acts of Duty and Loyalty: But they have had a quite different Effect; for many Perſons in whom the King hath repos'd great Truſt, (forgetting their Duty) have during the Courſe of this War miſrepreſented Perſons and Things to His Majeſty, and made a Prey of the Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick; and the better to cover and carry on their wicked Deſigns, have diſpenſed with the Law, perverted Judgment and Juſtice, pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhed innocent Perſons for doing their Duty; and preferred Cri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minals, to the great Hazard of the Common Safety: and from whence it is the Nation is now become ſo much in Debt.</p>
            <p>All theſe Evils would I have twice laid open the laſt Seſſion of Parliament; but was both times prevented by unjuſt and illegal Means, which cauſes me now to addreſs my ſelf to this moſt Auguſt Aſſembly for Relief: Theſe Corruptions being, I conceive, of much more dangerous Conſequence to the Government, (conſidering what a Faction there's in the Bowels of the Nation) than the War it ſelf; having taken ſuch deep root, and grown to that height, and ſo ſtrongly ſupported, as not to be remedied but in Parliament.</p>
            <pb n="iv" facs="tcp:110420:3"/>
            <p>I humbly conceive there's no Age can produce greater Inſtances of Oppreſſion and Injuſtice, than what the Nation now labours un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, and which in part are here ſet forth: But God hath not left us without Means, Ability, and Opportunity of removing theſe Evils; for there are great and remarkable Inſtances of Perſons (who have been found corrupt, and have made a Breach of their Truſt) that have been cenſur'd in Parliament; and it's they who are truly and properly the Great Council (and Phyſician) of the Nation; and as the Effect of whoſe great Wiſdom and Prudence, we now en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joy our Religion and Laws, and the Government hath been kept ſo long upon its Baſis. And when God is pleas'd to make publick Examples of ſome Men, and to puniſh them for their Cruelty and Oppreſſion, in ſuch Caſes he often makes uſe of weak and mean In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruments for the bringing his Purpoſes to paſs; that ſo the World may (as it were) viſibly ſee the hand of Providence: But I am not unſenſible of my own Inability to manage ſo great an <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taking as that is in which I have engag'd my ſelf, conſidering the great Intereſt and Power of my Adverſaries: So I have nothing to depend upon but the Juſtice of my Cauſe, the Goodneſs and Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bility of our Laws, and the Honour of the Repreſentatives of the Nation; which I humbly conceive will not be wanting to protect me, being able by Subſtantial Evidence to prove what I have ſet forth. I am, my Lords and Gentlemen,</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>
                  <hi>Your Honours moſt obedient Servant,</hi> Robert Crosfeild.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="account">
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:110420:3"/>
            <p>ALL Nations, even the moſt barbarous, have ever been jea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lous of their Liberty; and have rather choſe to die fighting in the Field, than be in Bondage to their Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſaries: And in the dark and elder Times of the World, we have Inſtances of Perſons that have ſacrific'd their own Lives for the Liberty and Safety of their Native Country; who are to be admir'd and pity'd, but not imitated: Yet Nature hath ſtamp'd upon the Minds of all Men, an Affection to their Native Soil; and thoſe who have deviated from it, have ever been look'd upon as Monſters, and treated accordingly. Now, notwithſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the manifeſt Danger the Government hath lain under during this War, it will appear that many Perſons in Places of the greateſt Truſt, have fallen from their Duty, and uſed ſiniſter and indirect Means to inrich themſelves, to the great waſte of the Publick Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure, and hazard of the Common Safety of the Nation: And thoſe whom I accuſe to have ſo done, are the Right Honourable the Lords of the Admiralty, Commiſſioners of the Navy, and the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners for the Sick and Wounded, and exchanging Priſoners at War. But before I enter upon any Matter relating to any of theſe Commiſſions, I ſhall inſert a Copy of a Depoſition of a certain Merchant which was laid before the Lords of the Admiralty, and is as followeth.</p>
            <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="deposition">
               <body>
                  <p>
                     <hi>H. B.</hi> of <hi>Goſport</hi> Merchant, maketh Oath,<note place="margin">This Depoſition with ſeveral o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers, (being be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Publick Staters of Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compts) I did deſire might be produced, but it could not be ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained; for which reaſon I print it.</note> That he hath been an Inhabitant in the Pariſh of <hi>Alverſtoke</hi> about Twenty eight Years; and his Houſe lying about half a Mile from the Water-ſide, and about a Mile and a half up the Harbour, he did for ſome Years ſerve their Majeſties Stores at <hi>Portſmouth</hi> with Rozin and Oil, and ſeveral other things: During which time, he hath often obſerv'd the Stores of that Yard were embezzled in conſiderable quantities, having met with ſeveral ſorts in his walks: And doth upon his Oath acknowledg, that he hath dealt for ſome thouſands of Pounds as his Neighbours have done in that Nature, that the Cuſtom of that Yard running on, and ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther improving for this three Years laſt paſt: And this Depo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nent finding great quantities was daily carried up and down a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:110420:4"/> Town, and other places; and ſeveral Lads bringing up the Mill-Lake ſome Pitch and Tar at a diſtance from this Deponent's Houſe, and offering him the ſame to ſale: after ſeveral times he queſtion'd where they had it; and one of them, by name <hi>John Hows,</hi> own'd to him they had it out of the King's Stores: He gave them fair warning of ſuch a dangerous Trade, and forthwith went and inform'd the Commiſſioner. And this Deponent farther ſaith, That he received fourteen Barrels of Tar from Capt. <hi>Richard New,</hi> Foreman of the Yard; of which fourteen Barrels, the Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioner ſtop'd four, which he this Deponent ſent over to <hi>Portſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mouth.</hi> Upon which, ſome Queſtion ariſing before the Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner about 27 Barrels of Tar, ſaid to be loſt out of the Yard; and he taking the four Barrels to be part of them, order'd them to be carried into Stores, notwithſtanding the ſaid <hi>New</hi> own'd to have had the fourteen Barrels aforeſaid, and clear'd the ſame to him at the <hi>Cuſtom-houſe,</hi> in the name of one <hi>Thomas Grant.</hi> And this Deponent farther ſaith, That it was here obſervable, that he the ſaid <hi>New,</hi> did very unwillingly own the Delivery of them to this Deponent before the Commiſſioner, till he was brought under a Neceſſity ſo to do. And farther he ſaith, When he inform'd the Commiſſioner, he uſed great Freedom with him, and remarked to him what Paſſages had fallen under his Obſerva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion; and told him unleſs greater Care was taken, the Nation would groan under its Burden before the War was half over; and that thoſe Goods could not be carried off without the Conſent of the Watch: And farther, he admir'd how the Store-keeper could paſs his Accompts. To which, in a ſlighting manner, he told him, this Deponent, it was all ſtuff. He farther inſiſted, the great Ones ſet on the little Ones; and as it was none of this Deponent's Concern, he did not deſire to bring Mens Names in queſtion, but that it was great pity things was not better look'd after. To which he reply'd, He deſir'd as little trouble as might be; and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſir'd to bring no body in queſtion, and car'd not a Fart for the Service, nor how ſoon he was out of the Place, for he hinder'd himſelf more than his Salary in another Way: That in two or three days after, the Commiſſioner<note n="*" place="margin">
                        <hi>Captain</hi> Wilſhaw.</note> ſent for this Deponent, and told him his Buſineſs was to conſine him aboard a Yatch: Upon which he deſir'd to know his Crime, and whether Bail might not be taken: To which he ſaid no. Then he asked him who accuſed him? He anſwered, that <hi>Thomas</hi> and <hi>Jonas Pod</hi> had ſworn they
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:110420:4"/> had ſold this Deponent ſeveral Barrels of Pitch and Tar which they ſtole out of the Stores: And this Deponent deſired to ſee them; and the Commiſſioner own'd he had given them leave to go away, but he had the Charge againſt him, this Deponent, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der their Hands and Seals. To which this Deponent told him, then he muſt have leave to ſay two things: Firſt, that he was a Knave to his Truſt, for letting the Principals run away: And Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>condly, a Fool for expecting to father their Rogueries upon him. And farther, this Deponent ſaith, That the ſaid Commiſſioner ſwore he would ſtop his this Deponent's Mouth; and came to him, and told him he was ſuch a Priſoner as was ſeldom or never heard of, for he ſhould eat, drink, and lie with him, and that he would not part with him this Deponent till he had brought him into a better Humour, or words to this effect: and accordingly car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried him this Deponent to his Houſe to Dinner, and there took Recognizance for his Appearance; but where, this Deponent knows not. And this Deponent farther ſaith, That he being in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>form'd by <hi>John Hows</hi> and others, that a Parcel of the beſt Deals, and ſome Tranſom Windows, was carried out of the Yard to <hi>Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ory</hi> in the <hi>Iſle of Wight:</hi> In which this Deponent being willing to ſatisfy himſelf, went to the Houſe, and bought four Load of Wheal of the Man that liv'd there: And then viewing the Houſe, ſaw a quantity of very ſine <hi>Pruſſia</hi> Deals ſawed, one Part for Wainſcot, the other for Flowers, and a great deal of other Stuff. And he this Deponent enquired of the Farmer, whether they were to be ſold? And he told him they were ſent there to repair the Houſe. And this Deponent farther ſaith, That the Second Day of <hi>Auguſt</hi> 1691, one <hi>David Aldridge</hi> came to this Deponent's Houſe, being on a Sunday; and he this Deponent juſt going to Church, the ſaid <hi>Aldridge</hi> deſir'd him to drink with him, for that he had ſomething to ſay to him this Deponent: Upon which, he invited him into his own Houſe; and ſitting down with him, af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter they had drank, there paſſed the following Diſcourſe between them. Mr. <hi>B.</hi> ſays Mr. <hi>Aldridge,</hi> I hear you and the Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner had a ſad Claſh on Thurſday laſt, and every one ſays you did him Juſtice, for certainly he's the greateſt Rogue that ever came into the Place; and had loſt his Commiſſion not long ago, when Mr. <hi>Trevor</hi> charg'd him with the Buſineſs of the Hawſer ſtop'd at <hi>Poſt-Bridg,</hi> but that he the ſaid <hi>Aldridge</hi> was prevail'd with by the Commiſſioner and ſome others, to ſay it was only about ten Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thom
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:110420:5"/> of an old Hawſer, fit only for Paper-ſtuff, and worth but two Shillings ſix Pence <hi>per</hi> hundred; when in truth he averr'd it to him this Deponent, to be as good as a new Hawſer, cut into fifteen Fathom pieces, for conveniency of being open'd, and worth a great deal more Money, which he the ſaid <hi>Aldridge</hi> declar'd he muſt have own'd if he had been put upon his Oath: But he was met with by Capt. <hi>Wilſhaw,</hi> and Mr. <hi>Southern</hi> and others, and per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwaded to ſay what he did, not being upon Oath.</p>
                  <closer>
                     <signed>H. B.</signed>
                  </closer>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
            <p>This Depoſition ſufficiently diſcovers to what a ſad Paſs the Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion is brought, in having the Publick Stores embezzled, and thoſe concerned in't that by Duty and Oath are oblig'd to preſerve them. I ſhall not now go about to ſay how ill a Man Capt. <hi>Wilſhaw</hi> is; it does ſo manifeſtly appear in this, and other of his Actions, that he has ſav'd me the labour of doing it.</p>
            <p>But I ſhall make it obvious to the World, that what he has done is but agreeable to the Practice of the Majority of the Commiſſioners of the Navy, who have either notoriouſly wronged the King, or have all a long ſupported others that have done it.</p>
            <p>But as I have charged three Commiſſions with making a Breach of their Duty and Truſt, ſo I ſhall relate ſomething in relation to each Commiſſion, yet no more than what has already (for the moſt part) been laid before the Lords of the Admiralty upon Oath, (tho hitherto ſtifled;) and what has not, I am ready to make ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear by good and ſubſtantial Evidence, and ſhall be as brief as po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſible in relating theſe things; and ſo only lay down the nature of the Crimes, and ſome of the Facts that have been committed by each Commiſſion; and afterwards give an Account by what Way and Means I was prevented laying open theſe things the laſt Seſſion of Parliament.</p>
            <p>Yet the Matters were ſo tranſacted, that I cannot put them is that Order I would, but ſhall place them in the beſt Method I can; and firſt lay down the evil Practices committed in the King's Yards.</p>
            <p>It is the general Practice in the King's Yards, for the Joiners and other Workmen, to be imploy'd in making of Tables, Cheſts of Drawers, Scrutores, and other Goods, out of His Majeſty's Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terials, and this by Order of the Chief Officers of the ſaid Yards. And the Officers do employ Men for making Models of Ships, (and
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:110420:6"/> other Works) ſome of which may be worth 2 or 300 Pounds, that are given away or ſold. The Iron Work is weigh'd in to the King twice or thrice over;<note place="margin">This prov'd be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Lords of the Admiralty upon Oath.</note> and it is the daily and open Practice of the Workmen and Labourers, to ſplit new Timber and Plank for Fi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring, for the Officers of the Yards and themſelves.</p>
            <p>I ſhall alſo relate ſome Matters referring to the Commiſſioners of the Navy.</p>
            <p>A certain Contract was made with a Merchant on behalf of the King for Stores for the Uſe of his Majeſty's Navy, but the Goods delivered were not of half the Value as by Contract they ought to have been: Yet notwithſtanding they were received by order of the<note n="*" place="margin">
                  <hi>Captain</hi> Wilſhaw.</note> Commiſſioner upon the place; but an Officer of Truſt ſeeing how groſly His Majeſty was abus'd therein, would not admit of it: upon which the Commiſſioner highly threatned him, and in ſome meaſure oblig'd him to a Compliance; which was to His Majeſty's Damage two or three hundred Pounds.</p>
            <p>Another Contract was made, and great part of the King's Tim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber brought into the Yard as Merchants Goods; which an Officer by the Yard obſerving, refus'd to receive: Whereupon a great Diſpute hapned between the ſaid Officer, and the Commiſſioner and other Officers, who were all very angry with him that he ſhould diſpute the Matter; and never left the Affair till they had gain'd their End, which was to His Majeſty's very great Loſs.</p>
            <p>Another fraudulent Contract was made on behalf of the King; wherein a Perſon's Hand was forged, (a<note n="*" place="margin">
                  <p>Captain <hi>Wilſhaw.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>All prov'd up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on Oath before the Lords of the Admiralty.</p>
               </note> Commiſſioner being con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern'd) but they were detected therein; yet His Majeſty ſuffer'd 2 or 300 Pound Damage, and had much more had it not been diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vered.</p>
            <p>A great deal more of this nature might be recited, but I think here are ſufficient Inſtances to convince all Men of the evil Practices of the Navy-board in reference to Contracts.</p>
            <p>But to proceed; Sometime after the Embezlement of the King's Stores in <hi>Portſmouth</hi>-Yard broke out, the Commiſſioners of the Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vy were at the Admiralty-board; and then and there did approve of the Proſecution of ſuch Perſons as had embezled the King's Stores, tho before they had done what in them lay to prevent thoſe Diſcoveries; and uſed their utmoſt Endeavour to ruin the Gentleman that was the occaſion of bringing thoſe Deeds of Dark<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs to Light, tho the Facts were ſo plain they could no longer withſtand it: But before that Matter came to trial, there were
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:110420:7"/> far greater Diſcoveries; wherein moſt of the Officers of <hi>Portſmouth</hi>-Yard were concerned, as likewiſe ſome Commiſſioners of the Navy (as has been related;) ſo that when the Trial at the <hi>King's Bench</hi> Bar came on, they appear'd in a body in the face of Juſtice to bring off the Criminals (whoſe Proſecution they had before ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prov'd); which they effected by ſetting up a falſe Book of Loans, and thereby impos'd upon the Court and Jury, (then the Attorney-General could do no leſs than bring a <hi>Noli Proſequi</hi> to ſtop all far<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Proceedings, His Majeſty having been at vaſt Charge in that Proſecution and no good enſued upon it); ſo that there were three other Informations<note n="*" place="margin">Wherein a mul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>titude of Perſons were concerned as Offenders.</note>, which at that time were dropt, and nothing done therein to this time.</p>
            <p>There's another Buſineſs alſo of the very ſame Nature: The Mayor of <hi>Portſmouth</hi> was fin'd 200 <hi>l.</hi> at <hi>Wincheſter</hi> Aſſizes for not returning the Recognizance in his hands: Upon which the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioner<note n="*" place="margin">Capt. <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhaw</hi> now Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioner in the <hi>Straits.</hi>
               </note> of <hi>Portſmouth</hi> ſends an Attorney along with the Mayor to go after the Judg to <hi>Salisbury;</hi> where he interceded with the Judg in the Name and by the Order of the Commiſſioner to excuſe the Fine, which was accordingly done, and the Commiſſioner bore all the Charge of that Journey;<note place="margin">All prov'd up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on Oath before the Lords of the Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miralty.</note> and the very original Note the Attorney gave him of the Charge, is now in the hands of the Lords of the Admiralty: So this Affair as well as the other fell, and never came to any thing.</p>
            <p>I ſhall relate another Paſſage of near kin to the foregoing: A certain Perſon here in Town, a Sail-maker by Trade, apply'd him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf to Sir <hi>Richard Haddock</hi> Comptroller of the Navy, and acquaint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed him that there were very great Embezlements made of the King's Canvas, to that degree that it was a very great Injury to the Trade in general, by being under ſold: And he told the Comp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>troller how and by what Means the Perſons might be taken with the Goods upon them;<note place="margin">Prov'd upon Oath before a Commiſſion of Council.</note> and if he would grant him a Commiſſion, he ſaid he would undertake the Matter himſelf: And after near an hour's Diſcourſe, Sir <hi>Richard</hi> ſlighted it, telling him, That Kings and Princes were born to be cheated; and ſo there was nothing done therein.</p>
            <p>And for Satisfaction of the Navy-board, I can ſhew a large Liſt of Seizures that have been made (no ways relating to the <hi>Portſmouth</hi> Buſineſs), yet no Proſecution either againſt Buyer or Seller.</p>
            <p>But during theſe Conteſts, in reference to the Embezlements of <hi>Portſmouth</hi>-Yard, it muſt be acknowledged the Lords of the Admi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ralty
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:110420:7"/> gave all imaginable Encouragement to ſuch as were inſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mental in thoſe Diſcoveries, with aſſurance of their Favour; which they enjoyed ſo long as the Right Honourable the Earl of <hi>Pembrook,</hi> my Lord <hi>Cornwallis</hi> and Sir <hi>Richard Onſloe,</hi> were in Commiſſion: but when their Lordſhips and Sir <hi>Richard</hi> left that Board, the Scene ſoon chang'd, and the Intereſt of the Navy-board prevail'd: Yet in the end, notwithſtanding all the ill Actions of the Commiſſioners of the Navy, their Lordſhips might have diſmiſt all ſuch Officers their Employment (being under their Juriſdiction) as appeared to be Criminal, and thereby given a great check to thoſe horrid Embezlements that were made; yet nothing was done therein: But on the contrary, the Commiſſioners of the Navy fell with great Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>olence upon thoſe Gentlemen who had made thoſe Diſcoveries, and ſuſpended them their Employments; and there was Subordination endeavour'd and ſet on foot by a Commiſſioner<note n="*" place="margin">
                  <hi>Captain</hi> Wilſhaw.</note>, and other foul Practices uſed againſt them (too long here to inſert) whereby to throw them out of their Employments; which after ſome time they did effect, yet no Crime (but their Faithfulneſs to His Majeſty and their Truſt) could be prov'd againſt them: And the Lords of the Admiralty, who ought to have protected them from the Violence of the Navy-board, ſlighted them, and turn'd them off with all imaginable Scorn and Contempt; and, to add to their Affliction, many of the moſt notorious Criminals were preferr'd.</p>
            <p>The Navy-board having by theſe foul and wicked Means cruſh'd all thoſe Perſons that had made any Diſcoveries of embezled Stores, there muſt from thence conſequently enſue infinite Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bezlements; and from that time I find not any Officer hath dar'd to oppoſe them, who have ever ſince acted as they pleaſe without Controll.</p>
            <p>But to proceed; Sometime after theſe unjuſt Succeſſes of the Navy-board, one Mr. <hi>George Everet,</hi> Shipwright, obſerving the great Abuſes committed in the King's Yards by the Mens waſting their Time, and their daily Deſtruction of Timber and Plank, appli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to the Lords of the Admiralty; and made a Propoſal to them whereby to ſave His Majeſty 100000 <hi>l.</hi> or more <hi>per Annum</hi> in the building and repairing the Royal Navy; and gave ſuch Demonſtra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion and Reaſon for what he ſaid, that the Propoſal had a general Acceptation, (being printed, and dedicated to the King and Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment;) yet notwithſtanding, he met with little Encouragement (as will appear by the Journal he has kept) from the Admiralty-board,
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:110420:8"/> being from time to time delayed: But after much Impor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tunity and Waiting, was referred to the Navy-board, before whom he often offered to prove the great Deſtruction and Waſte made of the King's Timber; and at one time produced twelve Witneſſes to prove the ſame, but they would hear but three of them, and very much ridicul'd what he offer'd, and threatned him with an Action of Scandal, whereby to cauſe him to deſiſt: which not pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vailing, and he not being under their Juriſdiction, they found them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves oblig'd to make a Report, (it being then a Year and a half after he made his Propoſal) which was tranſmitted to the Admi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ralty: But Mr. <hi>Everett</hi> was not permitted a Copy of it till half a Year after; and tho' it's too long here to inſert, yet it will appear how ſcandalous it was by the Memorial he deliver'd in anſwer to it, which is as followeth.</p>
            <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="deposition">
               <body>
                  <head>The humble Memorial of <hi>George Everett.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">To the Lords of His Majeſty's moſt Honourable Privy Council appointed a Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittee of Trade and Plantations.</note>THAT the ſaid <hi>George Everett</hi> having received a Copy of the Navy-board's Report, which their Honours made to the Lords of the Admiralty in anſwer to my Propoſals; and finding the ſame very large, and full of Reflections, Prevarications, and manifeſt Falſhoods, a full Anſwer to which I have drawn up rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy to produce: Yet I cannot conceive they would preſume to offer ſuch a Report to the Admiralty, or this moſt Honourable Board, unleſs with a Deſign to bring this matter to ſo great a Bulk, with long Reports, Anſwers and Replies, as to make your Lordſhips weary in examining into my Propoſal, tho of ſo great Advantage to the Publick Good: Therefore to ſave your Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhips much needleſs trouble, I ſhall here recite only three Parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culars in the Navy-board's Report; which if true, my Propoſals ought wholly to be ſet aſide, and I to ſuffer worſe Puniſhment than the Navy-board have already threatned to inflict upon me; which three Particulars are as followeth.</p>
                  <p>The Navy-board about the middle of their Report, expreſs themſelves in theſe words:</p>
                  <q>What Care is taken to prevent the Making and Carrying out any un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lawful Ships, the Inſtructions before recited have inform'd your Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nours,
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:110420:8"/> which is hoped is duly executed by the Officers; but if any of them are wanting therein, we ſhould be glad to know it, being altogether as willing to puniſh as reward, well knowing that on thoſe Hinges hang the good Management of the Affairs of the Navy.</q>
                  <p>'And about the next Leaf they alſo ſay theſe words:</p>
                  <p>And in caſe in his Obſervations any of them have acted other ways, <hi>(meaning the Officers of the Yards, or others, in embezling the Materials of old Ships)</hi> and he had thought ſit to have diſcover'd, and made it appear to us, he would certainly have met with ſutable Rewards, and Encouragement for it.</p>
                  <p>To which I anſwer, That I never declar'd the whole was em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bezled, but a great part of it; and in order to prove this, I did on the Fourteenth of <hi>May</hi> laſt, lay before the Commiſſioners of the Navy a Note containing the Names of near forty Witneſſes to prove theſe and other Miſcarriages committed in His Majeſty's Yards: Which being read, their Honours anſwer'd, that the Surveyor was not in Town, and that the ſame could not be deter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mined without a full Board.</p>
                  <p>After this I received a Letter from the Navy-board in theſe words:</p>
                  <floatingText type="letter" xml:lang="eng">
                     <body>
                        <opener>
                           <salute>Mr. <hi>Everett,</hi>
                           </salute>
                        </opener>
                        <p>THe Comptroller, and ſome other of the Members of this Board, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing ſuddenly to go out of Town again; and we being deſirous to do ſomething in your Buſineſs before we part, do deſire you to be with us on Saturday Morning next at Nine a Clock, and to bring with you the Perſons you have named, that can make appear the Abuſes in His Majeſty's Yards mentioned in your Paper.</p>
                        <p>We are your affectionate Friends,</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>
                              <list>
                                 <item>Tho. Wilſhaw,</item>
                                 <item>C. Sargiſſon,</item>
                                 <item>D. Liddell,</item>
                                 <item>John Hill,</item>
                                 <item>George St. Loe.</item>
                              </list>
                           </signed>
                           <dateline>
                              <hi>Navy-Office</hi> 
                              <date>
                                 <hi>20</hi> June, <hi>1694.</hi>
                              </date>
                           </dateline>
                        </closer>
                     </body>
                  </floatingText>
                  <p>Purſuant to this Order, I did on the 23d of <hi>June</hi> (being Satur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>day) attend the Navy-board in the Morning, with twelve Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, moſt of them Maſter-Shipwrights, in order to prove the
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:110420:9"/> ſaid irregular and extravagant Practices: But two of them and my ſelf, being only admitted, we did teſtify part thereof, and had a clamorous Debate of near three hours, till by degrees the Commiſſioners all departed, leaving one of the Evidences in the Board-Room, without order of withdrawing, or farther at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tending.</p>
                  <p>This my Attendance was the 23d of <hi>June,</hi> and the Navy-board's Report is dated the 27th of <hi>June,</hi> which is four days after; wherein their Honours pretended they had not heard of any of theſe Miſcarriages.</p>
                  <p>The third Particular is near the end of their Report; wherein the Commiſſioners of the Navy expreſs themſelves in theſe words:</p>
                  <floatingText type="letter" xml:lang="eng">
                     <body>
                        <p>Nevertheleſs this Wiſeaker ſays there may be <hi>100000</hi> l. a Year ſaved of what is now expended in the Navy in Shipwrightry, and Timber and Plank, if his Regulations, as he calls them, were put in execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion; tho upon our computing the whole Charge of ſuch Workmanſhip for all the ſix Yards together, with the Expence of Timber and Plank ſince the War, (which we have taken the pains to collect) we do not find the ſame amount to that Sum one Year with another.</p>
                     </body>
                  </floatingText>
                  <p>To which I anſwer, that this is a home Aſſertion, and ſtrikes at the very foundation of my Propoſal, and would repreſent me as a mad Man, that diſturbs your Lordſhips and the Nation with Propoſals to ſave 100000 <hi>l.</hi> a Year out of a leſs Sum: But I que<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtion not but to confute the Navy-board under their own hands and bring them as Witneſſes againſt themſelves. Therefore I moſt humbly pray, that the Commiſſioners of Accompts may be directed to lay before your Lordſhips an Account of the annual Charge of Building and Repairing the Royal Navy ſince the be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginning of the War; and likewiſe to direct the Lords of the Admiralty to lay before your Lordſhips a true Copy of the Eſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mate for the ſame Service, which their Lordſhips laid before the Houſe of Commons for the Year enſuing: For I may preſume to aſſert, that the Building and Reparing the Royal Navy, has for the Years paſt, and will for the Year enſuing, coſt the King a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove four hundred thouſand Pound <hi>per Annum:</hi> All which your Lordſhips will find atteſted under the Commiſſioners of the Navy's own Hands, if your Lordſhips will pleaſe to ſend for the aforemention'd Accompts and Eſtimate.</p>
                  <pb n="15" facs="tcp:110420:9"/>
                  <p>May it pleaſe your Lordſhips, if herein I have ſaid that which is falſe of the Navy-board, I am content to loſe all the Labour and Expence I have been at, and that my Propoſals ſhould be wholly rejected as falſe and ſcandalous: But if on the contrary, their Honours Report proves to be as I have here repreſented it<note n="*" place="margin">Their Lordſhips were pleas'd to look upon the Navy-board's Report to be ſcandalous.</note>, <hi>viz.</hi> full of Falſities and Prevarications, to weary and im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe upon your Lordſhips to ſet aſide Propoſals that may be ſo beneficial to the Publick Good and Safety of the Nation; then I ſhall humbly leave to your Lordſhips Juſtice, what Cenſure to paſs on the Navy-board, for making ſuch a Report to obſtruct the King's Service; which is ſign'd by no leſs than eight of their Members<note n="†" place="margin">R. Haddock, E. Dummer, G. Sergiſon, Tho. Wilſhaw, D. Liddall, J. Hill, S. Pett, G. S. Loe.</note>.</p>
                  <closer>
                     <signed>George Everett.</signed>
                     <date>
                        <hi>Febr.</hi> 25th 1695.</date>
                  </closer>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
            <p>There's no rational Man but will conclude this Propoſal of Mr. <hi>Everett</hi>'s practicable, tho the Navy-board took indirect Means to crade it.</p>
            <p>In ſhort, the Deſign of his Propoſal is no other but to root out all thoſe Evils which Cuſtom, and the Corruption of the Age hath produced; and no ways to alter the Oeconomy of the Navy, (as is inſinuated in the Lords of the Admiralty, and Commiſſioners of the Navy's Reports upon his Propoſal:) So that had it been put in pra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctice, by this time His Majeſty might have ſav'd three or four hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred thouſand Pound. And for the Commiſſioners of the Navy to aſſert the Building and Repairing of the Royal Navy did not an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nually amount to 100000 <hi>l.</hi> (which plainly appears to be a preva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ricating with Mr. <hi>Everett</hi>'s words) when they knew at the ſame time the Eſtimate given into the Houſe of Commons for the Wear and Tare of the Royal Navy for this preſent Year, was 780000 <hi>l.</hi> as appears by the Votes of the Houſe of Commons, is a moſt noto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rious Falſhood. One would therefore think, any Man that had the leaſt ſpark of Honour or Juſtice in him, would have been aſhamed to ſign ſuch a Report: And why the Lords of the Admiralty ſhould keep it ſo long by them, and not acquaint His Majeſty there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>with, I know not; however, it's plain it was never intended it ſhould have ſeen the light, it being forced from them, and the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſign being to weary out the Man, that he might waſte and ſpend his Subſtance, and ſo be forced to decline. A moſt effectual Way in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deed, and ſufficient warning to all Men to take care how they
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:110420:10"/> offer any thing for the Publick Service, tho never ſo advantagious. Beſides this Propoſal, Mr. <hi>Everett</hi> hath made appear, by a cloud of Witneſſes, the great Embezlements made in the King's Yards, and proved<note n="*" place="margin">Before a Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittee of Council.</note> many things in the face of the Commiſſioners of the Navy, and made them eat and drink Shame: Yet ſtill they ſtand as firm as a Rock, and ſay they have done no evil.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">The Sailors be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing inhumanly and barbarouſly trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, is the only true Cauſe why they ſo much de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cline the Publick Service.</note>The poor Sailers that venture their Lives and Limbs to ſerve their King and Country, and who are one of the greateſt Bulwarks of the Kingdom, have been all along moſt inhumanly and barba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rouſly treated, and they and their Families reduced to a miſerable and deplorable State, particularly by the wicked Practices of put<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting Queries and Runs upon their pay: For amongſt thoſe great numbers that are ſet on Shore ſick, thoſe that die, and others that continue ſick above thirty days, and thoſe ſent to the <hi>London,</hi> Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpitals for cure, who are thereby diſabled to return to their Ships, are for the moſt part made run: Others, whoſe Ships are ſailed before recovery, having gone on Board other Ships, are prick'd run from the Ship they were ſent from; and if a Seaman is turn'd over from Ship to Ship, and by that means has ſerv'd on Board four or five Ships in the Navy, yet if he happens to be prick'd run in the laſt Ship he ſerv'd in, he ſhall of conſequence be prick'd run in all the preceding Ships. By this means a Query or Run takes away a Man's Pay worſe than an Execution; and by the preſent Practice, no Seaman, or his poor Family, is at any certainty of having the Benefit of the King's Pay; for it is in the Power of the Captain, Captain's Clerk, Purſer, Clerk of the Cheque, Muſter-Maſter, or Clerks in the Navy-Office, when ever they pleaſe, to put a Run or Query upon any Seaman's Pay, without giving Reaſon for ſo doing, or the Name of the Perſon that put it: So that for theſe black pieces of Robbery, no one is liable to be called to accompt; but the poor Sailer is kept wholly in the dark, and he or his Wife may wait at the Navy-Office Month after Month, with Petitions to no purpoſe, till he has ſpent all his Subſtance: And when he begins to talk of his being thus cheated and robbed, he is threatned to be tried for his Life as a Mutineer. So that the Barbarity the poor Sailors do, and have ſuffered during this War, is unexpreſſible: The Blood of thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſands of Families are poured out as Sacrifices to the Covetouſneſs of thoſe whoſe Duty and Place it is to be their Guardians and Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tectors. By all which it's plain, that whatever good Laws may be made for the Increaſe and Encouragement of Seamen, will prove in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>effectual ſo long as theſe Practices continue.</p>
            <pb n="17" facs="tcp:110420:11"/>
            <p>Theſe Grievances have been at large ſet forth in Print by one Mr. <hi>Hodges,</hi> and a Scheme of their true Cauſe laid barefac'd be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Admiralty by Mr. <hi>Trevor</hi> in a Letter, and a Remedy for them propos'd in Writing to the Admiralty by Mr. <hi>Gibſon</hi> by order of a Committee of Council; and why there's nothing done, but this Fraud and Robbery ſtill practiſed and ſupported, is what no reaſon can be given for.</p>
            <p>Since neither Mr. <hi>Hodges</hi>'s, Mr. <hi>Trevor</hi>'s, nor Mr. <hi>Gibſon</hi>'s Papers before mention'd, have ever been exploded; the Lords of the Treaſury were ſo fully convinced of theſe Cheats, that their Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhips did by Warrant under their Hands in <hi>December</hi> laſt, appoint Mr. <hi>Gibſon</hi> to receive all Informations of Abuſes in Paiment of Sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mens Tickets, which doubtleſs would have put a ſtop to theſe wic<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ked Practices: Notwithſtanding which, the ſaid Mr. <hi>Gibſon</hi> has ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver been ſuffered to act, and ſo their Lordſhips good Intentions have been wholly defeated: But why their Lordſhips have not been able to put their own Orders in execution, is another ſtrange thing to me.</p>
            <p>I ſhall now lay down Mr. <hi>Trevor</hi>'s Letter, (before mention'd) by which the Reader will be ſatisfied as to the Humour and Temper of theſe Gentlemen, and after what rate things are and have been carried on: It is as followeth.</p>
            <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="deposition">
               <body>
                  <opener>
                     <salute>My Lords,</salute>
                  </opener>
                  <p>HAving conſider'd your Lordſhips Commands (to wit), That I lay before your Honourable Board a Propoſal to pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vent falſe Tickets and Powers for the future, I find my ſelf oblig'd humbly to repreſent the following Particulars, in order to ſatisfy your Lordſhips therein ſo far as I may at preſent, not be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing willing to take on my Shoulders (who am ſo much loaded already) ſuch a burden as an effectual Propoſal to that purpoſe muſt be: Therefore to let your Lordſhips ſee I am no Stranger to that Practice, ſuch Proceedings have been open'd to me long ſince by Officers of ſeveral Ships; one of which, whoſe Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcience was more tender, I remember told me, He trembled when he ſign'd the Ships Books, and conſidered what the Conſequence of a Diſcovery of this Practice might amount to; and gave me ſeveral Inſtances, telling me he muſt paſs them or be ruined; and that he was well inclin'd to lay down his Employment to be
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:110420:12"/> no longer under ſuch Circumſtances: Others declaring there was a Trade in faſhion, and they would take ſhare in it.</p>
                  <p>Your Lordſhips muſt find large Demonſtrations of it by what has paſſed, as well relating to the <hi>Mary</hi> as other Ships: The Diſtemper ſo well known, a Propoſal for the effectual preventing of it for the future carries no other difficulty with it than the Burden of the Intereſt againſt it, and might at any time have been redreſſed by juſt Men of no boaſted Skill in Buſineſs. And, my Lords, I think there are two at hand from the nature of the Crimes, and their being carry'd on ſo long: One of which I ſhall open to your Lordſhips, becauſe 'tis pertinent (in my weak Judgment) to the other Matters I lately laid before your Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nourable Board. For the ſecond, I pray leave to withhold it for the foregoing Reaſon; and becauſe, as I would not plow with any Man's Heifer but my own, ſo am I not blameable to ſecure to my ſelf if I can, ſome part of my dear-bought Experience, till it ſhall be my Duty to reform what I know to be amiſs, and can therein be ſupported.</p>
                  <p>Now, my Lords, it's moſt manifeſt that theſe Practices are not wholly carried on by a Combination of the Officers on Board Ships, (as is alledged) who cover theſe Crimes to avoid their own ruin, many of them to my Knowledg deteſting the Trade: It being well known what is, and has been the Practice of the Navy-Office, that if any ſuch Tickets and Powers happen not to be in the hands of any relating to that Office, yet ſuch may be found with their under-hand Agents, who tho of little Subſtance of their own, yet can buy up three or four thouſand Pound value in Tickets, that being the only way ſuch Frauds can long paſs, and ſuch true or falſe meet with no Obſtruction: But if any Complaint happens, 'tis no eaſy matter to have Right done; which is as plain as the Forgery in <hi>Gawler</hi>'s Bills<note n="*" place="margin">Prov'd before the Lords of the Admiralty.</note>, tho committed in the Navy-Office, nevertheleſs gave occaſion to the Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners of the Navy to promote the very Actor to be Clerk of the Cheque at <hi>Sheerneſs,</hi> to avoid other Matters like to break upon him, where he may carry on the Trade at pleaſure.</p>
                  <p>And if this be the caſe, which I preſume does fully appear, the moſt effectual Remedy againſt the Diſeaſe is to remove the Cauſe, I mean ſuch of the Commiſſioners of the Navy who have advo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cated, and paſſed by knowingly, and with deſign, notorious Crimes already diſcovered; and that done, there will remain no
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:110420:12"/> difficulty to form what muſt put a period to theſe Cheats, and all ground of ſuch lamentable Complaints as your Lordſhips and the Government have been long troubled with.</p>
                  <p>All which ariſe from the barbarous Uſage the innocent Subject have had, and a want of Tendency to their Complaints, and from falſe and deſigned Repreſentations of Matters; the Guilty being protected, excuſed, and carried through moſt ſcandalous and obvious Offences againſt the Law, and afterwards encoura<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged: which your Lordſhips find to be the Practice of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners of the Navy, by what I have long ſince and now lately laid before you; in particular, that of the Teſtimony of the Town-Clerk of <hi>Portſmouth,</hi> wherein your Lordſhips find a Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioner, after having uſed his utmoſt Skill to ſtifle ſo neceſſary a Diſcovery, paying the very Charges of diſappointing the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment, and getting off a Fine of 200 <hi>l.</hi> the better to conceal his own and others Crimes.</p>
                  <p>Now, my Lords, I muſt pray leave to relate, as well for the Information of ſuch of your Members as were not of your Board, as for reminding ſuch as were at the opening of my Caſe, and on the Proceeds of the Deſign againſt me by the Navy-board; they no leſs earneſtly juſtified the well and regular Management of <hi>Portſmouth</hi> Yard, than furiouſly proſecuted me, the better to cover the Miſcarriages I inſiſted on: In which it alſo lies prov'd before your Honourable Board, I rejected an Offer of two hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred Pounds Bribe to paſs them, the Perſon who made me that Tender (with other Accommodations) being nevertheleſs pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tected and preferred by them, tho it's plain both he and his Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther have from nothing advanced themſelves to great Eſtates by ſuch undue Proceedings: and I was not only advis'd if I deſiſted in that Matter, I ſhould be quieted in my Imploy, but in the very heat of the Proſecution againſt me the Expedient to ſilence all that Affair, was propos'd to me, to bring Capt. <hi>Wilſhaw</hi> to one of my Friends, and ſet him to rights there: Which being out of my power, it was carried on with the more Heat and Reſolution againſt me: And at the opening of the Embezlements there, which I had all along complained of, then did meer Shame (for I cannot take it any otherways) occaſion the Navy-board to own the Miſcarriages of <hi>Portſmouth</hi>-Yard to be great, and to recom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mend me by the Mouth of Mr. <hi>Sergiſon</hi> for Encouragement.</p>
                  <pb n="20" facs="tcp:110420:13"/>
                  <p>Which was very ſurprizing after a Deſign grounded on moſt palpable Perjury, and ſo ſcandalous a Repreſentation thereof, yet worſe than the Perjury it ſelf, from that Board.</p>
                  <p>And after all this to find ſeveral of the Commiſſioners of the Navy, in the face of Juſtice, bringing off Criminals by a Sham-Book of Loans, and thereby encouraging ſuch ſhameful Actions, and perſecuting ſuch as appear'd on the King's Part, even to the Death and Ruin of ſome, muſt ſurely aggravate theſe great Miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>carriages, when it ſo plainly appears the King is thus cheated by Authority.</p>
                  <p>I come now, my Lords, to the particular Crimes your Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhips have before you; which the Commiſſioners of the Navy have ſtifled or forgiven, contrary to Law; it being a common Practice, and of which there are not wanting yet more In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtances.</p>
                  <p>And next to the Diſcovery made by the Rope-makers, in which the poor Men think they have made a fair ſtep to their own Ruin; however, if it be follow'd it may put a great ſtop to that Trade.</p>
                  <p>But, my Lords, ſo long as there are Commiſſioners intruſted, who on ſuch Occaſions brand Diſcoverers for Informers, Rogues, and Villains, (tho they purſue Orders and Inſtructions) and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courage their being treated as the worſt of Men, ſetting up falſe and ſcandalous Informations againſt them, what end can be put to theſe Miſcarriages? Or till there is leſs Pride and Deſign at the Navy-Office, more Honeſty, and a Readineſs to hear, and relieve or ſatisfy all Complaints, without the accuſtomed Formality and Extorts of Money, with Attendance Month after Month to no purpoſe, it's not to be imagined any effectual Remedy can be applied. I am now humbly to pray that your Lordſhips will pleaſe to make report<note n="*" place="margin">To a Commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tee of Council.</note> of what I have laid before your Honourable Board; upon which I depend your Lordſhips in Juſtice will take occaſion to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>commend me for my Services, in being the Original and only Inſtrument in the way of my Duty, hardy enough to break through and bring on theſe Diſcoveries, and expoſing my ſelf and Family in the Execution of your Orders, to the great Perſecution and Preſſure we have long lain under;
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:110420:13"/> that ſo my Integrity may not effect the Ruin that has been indu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtriouſly endeavour'd by the Trading Multitude, Upon,</p>
                  <closer>
                     <salute>My Lords,</salute>
                     <signed>Your Lordſhips moſt faithful humble Servant, <hi>John Trevor.</hi>
                     </signed>
                  </closer>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
            <p>I ſhall now give farther Demonſtration of evil Practices in rela<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion to the Navy, by referring to what was publiſhed by order of the Lords of the Admiralty, as appears by the <hi>Gazette</hi> of the 7th of <hi>January</hi> 1694, which is as followeth:</p>
            <q>WHereas in purſuant of an Advertiſement in the Gazette of the <hi>10th</hi> of <hi>December</hi> laſt, a Paper ſign'd <hi>R. W.</hi> has been ſent to the Lords Commiſſioners of the Admiralty, offering to diſcover ſeveral Frauds and illegal Proceedings relating to Seamens Pay, in caſe His Majeſty ſhall be graciouſly pleas'd to extend His Pardon to the ſaid <hi>R. W.</hi> and others that come in with him to make out the ſaid Diſcoveries, for as much as they have been concerned in the ſaid Offences: His Majeſty being mov'd there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon, is pleas'd to promiſe His gracious Pardon to the ſaid <hi>R. W.</hi> and theſe concern'd with him in the ſaid Offences; Provided they make out the ſaid Diſcoveries, and that they have not been guilty of any thing of the like Nature before.</q>
            <p>There are four or five of theſe Advertiſements in the <hi>Gazette,</hi> ſome of them by order of the Commiſſioners of the Navy, but all of them to the ſame purpoſe: And any Man that has but half an Eye, may ſee a great deal of Fallacy in them, and that they have only the face of Juſtice, and were never intended to make Diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veries, but prevent them; as appears by the Clauſe at laſt, <hi>and that they have not been guilty of any thing of the like Nature before.</hi> Very pretty; there's no Man living but muſt conclude, that thoſe whoſe Conſcience will permit them to act ſuch things, have long practiſed them; and 'tis not probable they will ever make Diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veries unleſs they can ſit down ſecure, and have an ample and full Pardon: Therefore this does but encourage all thoſe that are guil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of theſe Practices, to proceed in the ſame, none being ſecure that ſhall go about to detect them.</p>
            <pb n="22" facs="tcp:110420:14"/>
            <p>Two of theſe Advertiſements I read at the Bar of the Houſe of Commons the laſt Seſſion of Parliament, (being order'd to appear there, as you will ſee by what enſues) and the whole Houſe was pleas'd to acquieſce in what I ſaid: And there's no Man ſo weak, but knows it to be the Practice of all Governments, fully to par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don Offenders (that make Diſcoveries) who have committed any Crime, even to the higheſt nature; and not only ſo, but often<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>times reward them, of which we have ſufficient Witneſs by Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons now living: And it matters not what end he has to himſelf that makes the Diſcovery, whether it be thro' Good-will or Ill-will, Love or Hatred, ſo it conduce to the Publick Good; it's then the Intereſt of the Government to give him all due Encourage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment.</p>
            <p>And until we come to act ſo, we can never think to proſper, but be in danger of ruin. Indeed as things are now managed, they look with an ill face; for notwithſtanding all the great Pretenſions to Loyalty, and the boaſted Skill of ſome Perſons, yet I ſay there have been great Diſcoveries laid before the Lords of the Admiralty long before theſe Advertiſements, (in reference to the wronging His Majeſty, and the poor Sailors) but no Proſecution of the Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons that committed the Facts.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Commiſſioners for Sick and Wounded.</note>But I fear I have dwelt too long upon theſe Matters, ſo ſhall pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed to the Commiſſioners for the Sick and Wounded: Againſt whom, one Mr. <hi>Baſton</hi> exhibited a Complaint, and twice prov'd them guilty, ſo far as was ſufficient to have given ſome of them their Paſſport (as they have done to many a poor Sailor) into the other World.</p>
            <p>When he firſt brought his Articles againſt them, they were by His Majeſty's Order referred to the Examination of the Lords of the Admiralty; and by their Lordſhips they were found guilty of what they were charg'd with: Upon which they petition'd His Majeſty for a Rehearing at the Council-board; which was granted, and they were again prov'd guilty of Breach of Truſt, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> as appears by the Council's Report. And beſides theſe Reports, there are other Matters<note n="*" place="margin">Whereby much innocent Blood has been ſpilt, and his Majeſty's Treaſure waſted; but they are too long here too inſert.</note> of dangerous conſequence ſworn and prov'd againſt them, which have long lain dormant in the hands of the Commiſſioners of Accompts; yet notwithſtanding all this, theſe Men are ſtill continued in Commiſſion, and Mr. <hi>Baſton</hi> deem'd the Offender.</p>
            <pb n="23" facs="tcp:110420:14"/>
            <p>I could lay down more things of this nature; but I am even a weary of raking in all this Filth, which muſt needs ſtink in the Noſtrils of all good Men.</p>
            <p>But I would not have any one now conclude, that all the Lords of the Admiralty, Commiſſioners of the Navy, and the Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners for the Sick and Wounded, are guilty of theſe things, for I verily believe otherways: Yet in the mean time, I can do no leſs than charge the whole Board, for in theſe Caſes the Major includes the Minor; and ſo there's no honeſt Gentleman can be any ways uneaſy for what I have done, or uſe Endeavours to prevent the fair Examination thereof, but promote it, thereby to remove the Scandal he ſeems now to lie under; for when there comes a Diſcri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mination, Truth will appear, as we have an Inſtance in the late Commiſſioners for Licenſing Hackney-Coaches.</p>
            <p>And now from all that has been related, it can no ways ſeem ſtrange how ſome Men have arriv'd to ſuch vaſt Eſtates: And if any Man impartially weighs the whole Matter, it muſt even aſtoniſh him to conſider how it's poſſible any Government ſhould be able to ſupport it ſelf ſo long as we have under ſuch Corruptions, and at the ſame time have ſo great a War upon it: Indeed we only owe the Preſervation of His Majeſty's Sacred Perſon and Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, to the Providence of God. However, the Nation feels the miſerable Effects of theſe Corruptions, by the many great and pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Debts: But I ſhall leave thoſe Gentlemen who have been the cauſe thereof, to the Juſtice of God and the Laws of the Nation, not doubting but they will meet with their due Reward, and be oblig'd to diſgorge their ill-gotten Goods.</p>
            <p>I think we may now fairly conclude, (without any breach of Cha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity) that the Commiſſioners of the Navy, and their Accomplices, plainly make a Prey of the Publick; and withal, not doubt but the Contracts made on behalf of the King, are for the moſt part frau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dulent; which has prompted them all along to protect thoſe Cri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minals that have embezled the Publick Stores, (nothing elſe could induce them to do it, unleſs they really deſign'd to ruin the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment, which then muſt be confeſſed to have been a moſt ef<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fectual way;) ſo that the Navy, which has been heretofore our Security, is now become a Gulf to ſwallow the Publick Treaſure.</p>
            <p>If any Man endeavours to lay theſe Evils open, he muſt undergo infinite Difficulties and Hardſhips, having a corrupt Party to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend withal; who by Time and Intereſt have knit and link'd them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:110420:15"/> ſo faſt together, that he's certainly cruſh'd by the Navy-board, or their Adherents; or otherways expoſed to the World (as I have been) as a Fool or Madman, or both; and render'd to His Majeſty as a vain idle Perſon, and look'd upon with as much Contempt and Scorn, as if he were the worſt of Criminals.</p>
            <p>I muſt confeſs I do not look upon this ill Treatment to be an Act of the Government, but that it arrives from the ſame Fountain all the reſt of the Evils have done: nevertheleſs, ſuch Proceedings are a Diſhonour to the Nation and Government, and may at laſt prove fatal to them.</p>
            <p>Some have aſſum'd to themſelves a Power of diſpenſing with the Law: Tho we have good and wholeſom Laws that are not put in execution, as thoſe againſt Embezlements, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> yet thoſe that en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deavour to have them put in practice, do even run themſelves up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on their own Deſtruction, as is ſeen by experience; he that diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers any Breach of thoſe Laws, being in far more danger than thoſe that committed the Facts, which is highly pernicious, and ſtrikes at the very foundation of the Government.</p>
            <p>I ſhall now relate ſomething I have cauſe to remember, and which is not altogether foreign to the Matter in hand. At the firſt opening of the Seſſion of Parliament, begun and held in the fourth and fifth Year of his Majeſty's Reign, I publiſhed a Book, en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tituled, <hi>England</hi>'s <hi>Glory Reviv'd;</hi> wherein I propos'd an Act of Tunnage for laying ſix Pence <hi>per</hi> Tun upon all Coaſters, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and likewiſe laid open the great Evil that attended the laying Embar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>go's upon Shipping, (which had been done every Year during the War until that time) giving full Demonſtration there was no cauſe for it; and ſo there has been none laid ſince, tho far greater occa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion than at any time before.</p>
            <p>All theſe Matters here related, (with ſome others) I would have laid open the laſt Seſſion of Parliament; and in order to it, declar'd in Print I could diſcover 2 or 300 thouſand Pounds of the Publick Money that had been embezled: Whereupon I was order'd to ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear at the Bar of the Houſe of Commons, which I did; and there declar'd the ſame, ſo I had the Aſſiſtance of that Honourable Houſe: Upon which I was ordered to withdraw; and in a quarter of an hour's time one of the Commiſſioners for Taking and Stating the Publick Accompts, came to me in the <hi>Lobby,</hi> and told me I had given great Satisfaction to the Houſe; and that I was referr'd to their
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:110420:15"/> Board, where I ſhould be heard with all imaginable Fairneſs: But ſeveral Gentlemen told me, that let my Cauſe be never ſo juſt, I muſt expect to be trick'd by that Board, none being more corrupt than they: Which ſeem'd ſtrange, conſidering the care taken in Parliament in the Choice of thoſe Perſons; and withal it being well known they had good Fortunes, I thought it morally impoſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble they ſhould ever be ſo corrupted as to act any thing againſt the Publick Good; yet, to my great Surprize, I found my ſelf miſtaken.</p>
            <p>But to proceed; in obedience to the Order of the Houſe, I waited on the Commiſſioners for Stating the Publick Accompts, and laid be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore them the great Injury done to the Souldiery by Agents and others in the Clothing of the Army, to the Diſcouragement of the Souldiery and Hindrance of His Majeſty's Service; and then would have laid before them the Corruptions of the Navy, afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>recited, but they would not receive it, all the Arguments I could uſe being to no purpoſe. All the Anſwer I could obtain, was, that it did not lie before that Board; and by way of Deriſion, they ſaid they might as well examine a Juſtice of Peace why he did not do Juſtice, as to enquire into thoſe Matters: But with Submiſſion, they ſhould have purſued the Order of the Houſe of Commons, which was to receive what I ſhould lay before them, and make report thereof with all convenient ſpeed; and not made themſelves Judges what was ſit for them to receive: for as His Majeſty and the Nation was injur'd, and the Publick Money and Stores em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bezled, it was their Duty to have heard me, and left the Houſe of Commons to be Judg. But they refuſing to hear me, put me to ſuch a Nonplus, that for ſometime I knew not what to do; and fearing I ſhould do little in the Houſe of Commons that Seſſion, I reſolv'd to petition the Houſe of Peers, and acquainted ſome of the Witneſſes with my Intention, who very well approv'd on't. Whereupon I drew up a Petition with five Heads thereunto annex'd, and preſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted it to a Noble Lord; which his Lordſhip was pleas'd readily to receive and deliver to the Houſe of Peers; where it was receiv'd with much Freedom and Readineſs by their Lordſhips, and forth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>with order'd to be read. And that the enſuing Matter may be the better underſtood, I have here ſet down a true Copy of the ſame, which is as followeth.</p>
            <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="petition">
               <body>
                  <pb n="26" facs="tcp:110420:16"/>
                  <head>To the Lords Spiritual and Temporal in Parliament Aſſembled, The humble Petition of <hi>Robert Crosfeild,</hi>
                  </head>
                  <opener>Sheweth,</opener>
                  <p>THAT your Petitioner having lately dedicated and preſented to your Lordſhips a Book entituled, <hi>Great Britain</hi>'s <hi>Tears;</hi> ſetting forth the great Abuſes committed in the Government by Perſons in Places of Truſt, and alſo the Embezlement of the Publick Treaſure, to the great Hazard of the common Safety of the Nation: And your Petitioner having in the Paper annex'd, drawn up ſome part of the ſaid Miſcarriages and Grievances that the Nation now labours under, relating to the Royal Navy, and being ready by good and ſubſtantial Evidence to prove the ſame before this moſt Honourable Houſe:</p>
                  <p>Your Petitioner therefore moſt humbly prays that your Lordſhips will pleaſe to hear and examine the ſaid Grievances, that the Offenders may have ſuch Puniſhment, and the great Numbers that are oppreſſed ſuch Relief, as to your Lordſhips Wiſdom ſhall ſeem meet. And your Petitioner ſhall ever pray, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p n="1">1. That the preſent Commiſſioners for Sick and Wounded Seamen, and Exchanging Priſoners at War, (depending on the Admiralty) not regarding Inſtructions, or the Good of the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment, have committed groſs Ennormities; as Holding or Conniving at an unlawful Correſpondence with the French, and Wronging both the King and Subject in their Accompts, with other great Miſcarriages: All which has been about a Year ſince laid in Writing before the Secretary of State by one Mr. <hi>Baſton,</hi> and by the King's Command examin'd before the Lords of the Admiralty, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And it will appear, that the ſaid Commiſſion
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:110420:16"/> has been very injurious to the poor Sailors in particular, and very detrimental to the Government in general.</p>
                  <p n="2">2. That the Lords of the Admiralty, and Commiſſioners of the Navy, have acted contrary to the Publick Good, by countenan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cing, ſupporting, and preferring Criminals; and on the contrary, perſecuting the Diſcoverers, and turning juſt Men out of their Offices.</p>
                  <p n="3">3. That their Lordſhips have had great Diſcoveries laid before them of Embezlements, and other great Frauds committed in the King's Yards, attended with Forgery and Perjury.</p>
                  <p n="4">4. That it is manifeſt ſome of the Commiſſioners of the Navy have in that Office advanced themſelves from Salaries of 30 <hi>l. per Annum</hi> to vaſt Eſtates, having paſſed great Frauds, and total<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly diſcouraged the Diſcovery of embezled Stores, to the great waſte of the Publick Treaſure.</p>
                  <p n="5">5. That it has been a long Practice in the Navy to make out falſe Tickets and Powers, ſuſpending and delaying the poor Sai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lors in their juſt Paiments, to the general Diſcouragement of them, and Starving their Families.</p>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
            <p>Upon the Reading of this Petition, Mr. <hi>Baſton</hi> and I were call'd to the Bar of the Houſe, to know if we could make good what I had ſet forth, (in reference to the firſt Head): Which we aſſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting, in a little time their Lordſhips were pleas'd to order me to give in a Liſt of my Witneſſes; which I did in part, and ſo pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeded to the Examination of ſome of them upon the firſt Head, which was done with all imaginable Fairneſs. But there being ſome Depoſitions, and other Papers in the hands of the Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners of Accompts, which I deſired might be tranſmitted to the Houſe of Peers: They thereupon ſent their Secretary with ſome Papers, who ſaid the Depoſitions were long, and would be ſo vo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>luminous as they had not leaſure to draw them out; ſo begged the Favour they might have the Examination of the Matter: Which was ſoon granted by their Lordſhips, and an Order accordingly iſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſued out, bearing date the 20th of <hi>March,</hi> for their taking the Exa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mination of the firſt Head; and for them to make their Obſerva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions upon the ſame, and to tranſmit both to the Houſe of Peers. And by another Order of the 21ſt of <hi>March,</hi> they were order'd to take the Examination of the ſecond and third Heads, and then to tranſmit the ſame to the Houſe.</p>
            <pb n="28" facs="tcp:110420:17"/>
            <p>But when I came to underſtand that the Commiſſioners of Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compts had drawn this Matter to them again, which they had be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore rejected, I had juſt cauſe to fear they had a Deſign to prevent the Diſcovery of all theſe evil Practices; yet how to help my ſelf I knew not, not knowing how corrupt that Board might be: All which put me to a great ſtand, foreſeeing I ſhould be baffled.</p>
            <p>But I cannot omit relating one remarkable Paſſage, which is worthy of Obſervation: Upon the Reading my Petition in the Houſe of Peers, and Order being given to call me to the Bar of the Houſe, and a Door-keeper calling me with a loud Voice, one of the Commiſſioners of the Publick Accompts then accidentally paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing by, and hearing my Name call'd, met me in the Painted-Chamber juſt as I was going into the Houſe, (an honeſt Gentleman, only has wanted Reſolution to withſtand the Charms of theſe <hi>Si<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>renes</hi>); who ſeem'd to be in great Confuſion and Diſorder of Mind, and was taken with ſuch a Fit of Trembling as <hi>Belſhazzer</hi> was when he ſaw the Hand-writing upon the Wall, not being able to hold one Joint ſtill; and asked me if I accuſed the Juſtice of their Board? But I ſoon put him out of his pain by aſſuring him I did not; only I did ſeek for Relief and Juſtice, which I could not ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain at their Board.</p>
            <p>Thus we may ſee when Men are ſurprized, and a Guilt attends their Actions, how all their little Arts and Intrigues fail them.</p>
            <p>But to return; Finding my ſelf oblig'd to proceed with theſe Gentlemen the Commiſſioners of Aecompts, Mr. <hi>Baſton</hi> and I wai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted on one of them at his Houſe, whom we knew to be a leading Man at that Board; and acquainted him that we had not been well treated by their Board before, yet hoped we might now have things fairly examined. He bad Mr. <hi>Baſton</hi> (whoſe Buſineſs was firſt to come on) not trouble himſelf with what was paſt, he ſhould be fairly treated; for, ſays he, we'll take care to put our Finger upon the right place, (that was his Expreſſion.) Which I muſt confeſs they did to the purpoſe, but to a wrong end, having thro' the whole Courſe of this Examination ſhew'd much Injuſtice and Partia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity; for when they went upon the Examination of the firſt Head, they brought three Informations (I can call them by no other name) againſt Mr. <hi>Baſton;</hi> the Conſequence of the firſt being High-Treaſon, and put him upon his Oath to clear himſelf from the other two: And when I waited on theſe Gentlemen firſt, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the 23d of <hi>March,</hi> I deſir'd that the Witneſſes as to the ſecond
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:110420:17"/> and third Heads, might have Precepts iſſued out for them, many of them living in the Country at a great diſtance: Upon which the Board did aſſure me they would take care it ſhould be done; and as we proceeded upon the firſt Head, I deſiring to know whether the Witneſſes were order'd to appear in relation to the ſecond and third Head, was ſeveral times anſwer'd, Care was taken therein; but I ſound it otherways, there being no Precepts iſſued out for any Witneſſes in the Country till the 12th of <hi>April:</hi> Yet during the time of examining the firſt Head, the Board ſent for Mr. <hi>Trevor</hi> here in Town, who was a Witneſs to the ſecond and third Head; and cauſing them to be read, asked him what he knew concerning them? He ſaid he knew them to be true, and that they would be fully prov'd by good and ſubſtantial Evidence, and that things would appear to be much blacker than they were repreſented: With which they ſeem'd to be well pleas'd, and upon the 18th of <hi>April</hi> we began to examine Witneſſes upon the ſecond and third Head, and ended the 19th of the ſame Month; the Board declaring they bad ſo much Buſineſs upon them, they could proceed no farther that Seſſion of Parliament. So there was little Progreſs made there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in, the moſt material Witneſſes not being examin'd: But during the Examination of theſe things, the Board did what in them lay to ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dicule the whole Affair; and one of the Commiſſioners who ſaid he'd lay his Finger upon the right place, affirm'd the whole Matter was but a Contrivance of Mr. <hi>Trevor</hi>'s, and nothing in it. I ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quainted Mr. <hi>Trevor</hi> with it; who afterwards told the Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners that a Gentleman of that Board had ſaid that thoſe Arti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cles I had brought were a Contrivance of his: He ſaid whoever did it acted very unworthily, for that it was none of his doing; and offer'd them his Oath, ſaying he had laid his Matters elſewhere: and farther told them, the Articles were true if they had but a mind to hear them: Upon which, the whole Board was ſilent, not one Man making any Reply; and the Gentleman who ſpoke the words hung down his Head as if he had been aſleep, not that he valued what was ſpoken, but his Conſcience ſmote him.</p>
            <p>After theſe Things remain'd without any farther notice, till <hi>July</hi> the 12th, when I receiv'd a Letter from their Secretary, requiring me to be at the Office the 18th: Where I did appear, and ſent in my Name to the Board: Upon which, their Secretary came to me with a Meſſage; which I did not think fit to receive from him, ſo ſent in my Name again, deſiring to know if they had any farther
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:110420:18"/> Commands. Whereupon I was call'd in, and told by the Chairman, that if I knew of any Perſons that were guilty of any Crimes (in relation to thoſe Articles I had brought) that were not within His Majeſty's late Act of Grace, if I would lay it before that Board, I ſhould be heard: This was twice repeated to me, for fear I ſhould forget it<note n="*" place="margin">Some Perſons have left the good old Way, and made new Paths to themſelves; firſt cruſh a Man, then by their E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſaries, ſpread abroad he can prove nothing: yet we ſee Time and Patience brings Truth to light, to the Shame and Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>honour of its Repugners.</note>.</p>
            <p>But now, with theſe Gentlemens leave, neither they nor I had any thing to do with the Matter, as to judg who was pardon'd and who was not; therefore this was only an Evaſion to prevent the farther opening thereof: for as the Articles were brought before the Act of Grace was paſſed, ſo with Submiſſion it was their Duty to have receiv'd the whole Information; and if any Perſons were afterwards found to be criminal, and within the Act of Grace, it were ſufficient for them to plead it; and then the Nation might know and ſee who it was had abus'd them for ſo many Years run<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning, and for the future take care to prevent the like Evils.</p>
            <p>But this Method taken by theſe Gentlemen, was a Means utterly to overthrow all Diſcoveries of this kind; and the Kingdom like to be cheated, and kept as much in the dark as it has been hitherto.</p>
            <p>For ſhould I have proceeded only upon ſome part, it would have appear'd but a lame obſcure Buſineſs, (eſpecially as it might have been manag'd by them;) ſo in courſe it would be thrown out and rejected by the Houſe of Peers as a Matter frivolous and idle: and if I did not proceed, it were ſtill the ſame, (I having ſix Months time to do it in) their Lordſhips might then with a great deal of Juſtice throw it out; and after that no Puniſhment would be thought too great for me.</p>
            <p>Therefore theſe Gentlemen have put me upon a Neceſſity of pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſhing theſe things; not only in reference to my own Safety, but in Juſtice to my Native Country: And I am ſorry they, of all Men, ſhould not behave themſelves more like Engliſhmen, having all a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>long had the Character of being worthy Patriots of their Country.</p>
            <p>For if we may judg of things by the Actions of theſe Gentlemen and others, it's a grand Queſtion, whether there's any ſuch thing as Religion, or we have any Laws or no? And by the ſame Rule diſputable, whether I am a Man or a Woman? But let us not thus deceive our ſelves; for we muſt never expect to proſper until we make Duty, and not Intereſt, the Rule of our Actions.</p>
            <p>And altho' God has been pleas'd to give Succeſs to his Majeſty's arms this laſt Campagn, yet it can be no Argument for the Conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nuance
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:110420:18"/> of theſe Corruptions, thereby to oppreſs the Nation and gra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tify the Appetite of particular Perſons<note n="*" place="margin">
                  <hi>Jeremiah 5.26, 27, 28, 29.</hi> wherein is lively ſet forth our pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent State and Condition, ſo worthy the Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ruſal of every Man.</note>, Matters being ſtill dubi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous, the War not being brought to a period; but the Event thereof uncertain, and the Neceſſities of the Government apparently great: therefore we can no ways infer from thence the War will have a happy Iſſue; but may rather juſtly conclude, in the end God will puniſh us if we maintain and ſupport ſuch Cruelty and Oppreſſion.</p>
            <p>Yet notwithſtanding, if by theſe evil Practices the Nation ſhould be thrown into a Civil War, (which is no unreaſonable Suppoſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, but what we have juſt cauſe to fear, conſidering what a Facti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on we have in the very Bowels of us, which theſe Corruptions nouriſh, and from whence they gain ſtrength;) none probably would be more ready to draw their Sword in defence of their Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try, than the Authors and Abettors of theſe Corruptions: From whence we may ſee the Frailty of Humane Nature, and the miſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable Effects of Pride, Ambition and Covetouſneſs, which darkens the Underſtandings of Men, while they make ſuch eager purſuit af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Riches; and it's that which hath produced all theſe great E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>normities.</p>
            <p>If theſe things are paſſed over with Silence, the Nation can have no Security, by reaſon it will embolden Offenders, and excite and prompt others to commit the like Crimes <hi>ad Infinitum:</hi> For it's ſeen by Experience, the Generality of Mankind are more inclined to follow Example than Precept; but the fear of the Law and Puniſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment to enſue, puts a Bridle upon the Appetite and Deſires of Men, and keeps them cloſer to their Duty than the Dictate of Conſcience does; and that excellent Saying of <hi>Polybius</hi> ought never to be for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gotten: <hi>I believe</hi> (ſays he) <hi>that Nature her ſelf has conſtituted Truth as the ſupream Deity, which is to be ador'd by Mankind; and that ſhe has given it greater force than any of the reſt: for being oppos'd, as ſhe is on all ſides, and Appearances of Truth ſo often paſſing for the Thing it ſelf, in behalf of plauſible Falſhoods; yet by her wonderful Operation ſhe inſinuates her ſelf into the Minds of Men, ſometimes exerting her Strength imme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diately, and ſometimes lying hid in Darkneſs for Length of Time; but at laſt ſhe ſtruggles through it, and appears triumphant over Falſhood.</hi>
            </p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
